#### Contact

ruslan@amirov.dev

www.linkedin.com/in/ruslanamirov-0268bb80 (LinkedIn) github.com/tengri (Personal)

### Top Skills

**TypeScript** 

React.js

Node.js

#### Certifications

Data Structures in JavaScript: Visualizations & Exercises

Figma Design Foundations
Professional Training Course

A Deep Dive into React Hooks

Base of Agile methodology

Learn React Native Course

# Ruslan Amirov

Senior Frontend Developer

Almaty, Kazakhstan

## Summary

A highly experienced and skilled Lead Frontend Developer with experience in working with international teams.

An expert of HTML, CSS, TypeScript, React, Node.js, and more. Exhibits a work ethic that focuses on paying attention to detail, problem-solving, effective customer communication, and respectful collaboration across departments.

Encourages a diverse and respectful workplace.

## Experience

Stenn Technologies Senior Frontend Developer April 2022 - Present (2 years 6 months)

England, United Kingdom

- Developed a new product Revenue Based Financing from scratch to release(https://rbf.stenn.com/)
- Made redesign of the RBF App Onboarding, including developing reused component Connections.

Tinkoff Bank

Senior Frontend Developer October 2019 - April 2022 (2 years 7 months)

Moscow, Moscow City, Russia

Developed frontends for ATMs and an administrative panel that controls ATMs.

- Researched incidents from ATM's clients to avoid image losses for the company.
- Fixed many critical bugs which caused to decrease number of incidents with ATMs and as a result saved the company's resources.
- Made redesign of ATM's Web App, including support of new ATMs with 4k displays which caused an increase in customer satisfaction.
- Successfully migrated the administrative panel from Webpack to Next.js.
- Automated many processes of service of ATM, which allowed to double the numbers of AMTs without hiring a support team.

#### Bitfury

Middle to Senior Full-stack Developer May 2018 - October 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Amsterdam, North Holland, Netherlands

Developed frontend for blockchain systems on Exonum.

- Developed an inner document management system.
- Developed the inner tool (frontend + backend) to work with blockchains based on Exonum.
- Developed the front end of a blockchain app to manage the order of entering Kazakhstan's kindergartens to avoid corruption.

Sberbank-Technology
Junior to Middle Frontend Developer
February 2016 - May 2018 (2 years 4 months)

Moscow, Moscow City, Russia

Developed the bank system for small and medium businesses using on TypeScript/React/Redux.

- Migrated the app from Javascript to Typescript.
- Migrated the app from Reflux to Redux.
- Added localization to the bank system
- Added a currency payment to the bank system.

## Education

Bauman Moscow State Technical University

Master's degree, Computer Science · (September 2009 - July 2015)

Bauman Moscow State Technical University
Master's degree, Computer Science (2009 - 2015)